# **Cao Viet Thang (Viktor Cao)**

## **Web Developer**

Phone: +84 366.884.581 (VN) Email: cvthang56th2@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thang-cao96/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/thang-cao96/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a web developer with +5 years of experience in designing, developing, and maintaining web applications (including 2 years of experience in front-end web development in a pixel-perfect manner).

I am considered a team-player because I like to help other and tend to work well within the group. I can also do some mentoring tasks and do code reviews for other team members. I always willing to learn new technologies.

Experienced in Waterfall and Agile (Scrum / Kanban) methodologies.

Can communicate in English.

## **Specialties**

- Proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies.
- Strong understanding of the entire web development process.
- Quick learning, researching and applying new knowledge.
- Good at teamwork and communication, encourage and motivate team members for improving team spirit well.
- Have ability to work as T-shaped person in Scrum Team

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### Programming Languages:

- JavaScript
- PHP
- HTML5, CSS3

#### Frameworks/ Platforms:

- Vue.js (2,3), Vuex, Pinia, Nuxt.js, Vue testing
- React.js, Redux, Zustand, Next.js,
  Gatsby.js, React testing

- Webpack, Babel, ES6, Vite.
- Express.js
- Hapi.js
- Nest.js
- jQuery, GSAP, Bootstrap
- Wordpress, Laravel, Drupal
- PHPUnit
- Cypress and Cucumber.js
- Puppeteer

#### • Database Management Systems:

- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Firebase Firestore

#### Cloud:

- AWS (basic)
- Hostinger
- Firebase

## • Version Control:

- Git
- Docker

### Languages:

English: communicateVietnamese: native

#### Soft Skills:

- Time management
- Teamwork

#### Others:

- Good understanding of OOP methodologies, SOLID principles, design patterns
- Experience with Agile and Scrum development process
- Ability to use Photoshop. Can do simple design: logo, banner, poster....

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES**

## Nha Trang University (Nha Trang city, Viet Nam)

Major: Information Technology

- University Degree (09/2014 to 09/2018)

Degree grade: Good - GPA 3.35/4

- Master's Degree (06/2020 - present)

Graduation thesis: Certificate Management based on Blockchain, which I deployed to AWS.

Github: <a href="https://github.com/cvthang56th2/CertsChain">https://github.com/cvthang56th2/CertsChain</a>

- Microsoft Ofice Specialist: Word 2013 (2017)
- Microsoft Ofice Specialist: Powerpoint 2013 (2018)
- <u>Certified Vue Developer</u> (by VueAcademy 2023)

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

### **9thWonder Vietnam**, Nha Trang city, Vietnam

06/2018 - 06/2023

A website development company in Nha Trang with 50+ employees, formerly a major Digital Agency in the United States.

Watch me at 9thWonder VietNam

**Position:** Full Stack Node.js Developer (06/2018 – 12/2021)

• **Project**: Mazi (06/2018 – 12/2021)

**Project description**: A software system for all production and talent management needs. From research and asset management to contract creation and job organization.

## Team Size: 12 Responsibilities:

- Developed reuseable components for front-end and created APIs for front-end use.
- Wrote tests such as E2E, unit tests, and component tests.
- Participated in discussions and offered solutions to solve problems.

**Used technologies:** Node.js, Vue.js, Hapi.js, pdftk, MongoDB with Mongoose, Redis, ElasticSearch, Jest, Cypress, Cucumber.js and AWS (EC2, S3).

**Position:** Web Developer (01/2022 – 06/2023)

## • Project: Tool check email (01/2022)

**Project description:** 9thwonder Vietnam supports creating html emails for many different customers, each html email needs to pass many different rules and validations to complete. And I created this tool to validate these html emails, it reduces time for both developers and testers.

## Responsibilities:

- Design UI/UX and create a page that helps input html emails and validates the input according to all the rules.
- Updated feedback from other developers and testers

**Used technologies:** HTML5, CSS3, TailwindCSS, JavaScript.

## • **Project: Cypress Template** (02/2022)

**Project description:** Cypress source code template helps to test many common test cases in a new website. Can be modified to suit site requirements. This can be considered the first brick of Automation Testing at the company.

#### Responsibilities:

- Build source code structure, write utility functions to support test writing, write test code for common test cases.
- Collaborate with testers to suggest common test cases
- Create a tool to automatically generate feature/scenario files.
- Help newbies and testers how to write automation testing, how to write Cucumber and Cypress.

**Used technologies:** Cypress, Cucumber.js

## • **Project: Bosley** (03/2022)

**Project description:** Official website of Bosley - the largest hair restoration practice in the United States and the recognized leader in the industry.

#### Responsibilities:

- Participated in writing automation tests for website.
- Create a tool to automatically generate feature/scenario files, used to test the website's scheduling process. And write test code for these features/scenarios.

**Used technologies:** Node.js, Cypress, Cucumber.js

• **Project: Encompass** (04/2022)

**Project description:** Official website of Encompass Technologies - an American multinational enterprise resource planning software corporation, with headquarters in Fort Collins, Colorado.

**Responsibilities:** Design fields, build components, and query data for components. **Used technologies:** React.js, Gatsby.js, GraphQL and Contentful as the database.

Project: XOS (05/2022)

**Project description:** Simulated the entire UI of an XOS machine (an X camera).

Responsibilities: Worked alone as the only programmer for the project.

**Used technologies**: Vue.js 3 and Tailwind CSS.

Projects: Wordpress websites (From 06/2022 – 03/2023)

Projects description: Websites built using CMS WordPress.

Lived sites: **BrainCare**, **ExakTime**, **Gravina Windows**, **Syndeo Institute** 

## Responsibilities:

- Build modules, create custom widgets, all front-end is built in perfect-pixel manner.
- Optimize website performance by following Google's pagespeed.dev
- Write code tests such as E2E and unit tests.
- Create plugins and tools to help testers work faster.

**Used technologies:** PHP, Drupal, WordPress, Elementor, Vue.js, Cypress, Cucumber.js, jQuery, GSAP, Tailwind CSS, PHPUnit and MySQL.

• **Project: Hearsay** (03/2023)

**Project description:** create capabilities that help customers build their websites for Hearsay Social - a cloud-based social customer relationship management (CRM) solution that caters to financial services businesses and helps them to manage their interactions with existing and prospective customers.

#### Responsibilities:

- Participated in phase 2 of the project, updated code to allowing customers to customize colors, text, and some other system functionality.
- Updated cron job generate customer's site according to new requirements.
- Wrote code tests such as E2E and unit tests.

**Used technologies**: PHP, Drupal, Cypress, and MySQL.

• **Project: VIOC Oil Change** (04/2023)

**Project description:** website of a VIOC Oil Change's branch - a company that provides preventive maintenance services for many different types of automobiles.

**Responsibilities:** joined and optimized APIs after migration, fixed and updated quering for a table (MySQL) with approximately 20 million records.

**Used technologies:** PHP, WordPress, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery.

#### • Project: Design preview for Honda's website (05/2023)

**Project description:** Honda is a big company in motorbikes, so the pages used to introduce their new models will be very careful. Figma is a good tool but the preview animation in this tool is not smooth, so we convert to html to make it smoother. Makes the preview design experience more enjoyable. And then these html can be used for production.

**Responsibilities:** convert some of Figma's modules to html, including animations.

**Used technologies:** HTML5, CSS3, TailwindCSS, Nunjucks, JavaScript

Freelancer 2019 - present

Based on my skills and I enjoy participating in web application projects. So, most of my freelance projects are web applications and working with a team of 5 members.

Project: Shopee CRM, Shopee Analytics (08/2021 – 04/2022)

**Project description:** The Shopee CRM supported sellers on Shopee to manage and analytics goods, orders, customers, and automatically message customers

Responsibilities: design database, design UI/UX, code both front-end and back-end.

**Used technologies:** Node.js, Vue.js (front-end), Nest.js (back-end), and MongoDB with Mongoose.

## Project: DAO Management and DAO Chat (03/2022 – 08/2022)

### **Project description:**

- DAO Management, a system for managing employees in the company DAO Entertainment and assets such as audio and video files stored in the cloud securely.
- DAO Chat, a web app similar to Facebook's Messenger with features such as single chat, group chat, channel chat, and the ability to send text messages, images, and sounds.

**Responsibilities:** design database, design UI/UX, code both front-end and back-end.

**Used technologies:** Node.js, Vue.js (DAO Chat), React.js (DAO Admin), Nest.js (back-end), MongoDB with Mongoose, Firebase (Firestore, Storage, FCM, Functions), and Google Drive API.

• **Project: Hotato Extension (Chrome)** (04/2022 – 06/2022)

**Project description:** Which supported Shopee users to view more advanced information about products such as sale history, sourcing similar products, and adding products to their own

**Responsibilities:** design database, design UI/UX, code both front-end and back-end.

**Used technologies:** Node.js, Vue.js, Vite, Shopee API, Nest.js (back-end), and MongoDB with Mongoose

Project: Coffee Shop Management (05/2023 – 06/2023)

**Project description:** manage a small coffee shop

**Responsibilities:** design database, design UI/UX, code both front-end and back-end.

**Used technologies:** Vue.js, Firebase (Firestore, Hosting)

### **PASTIMES AND ACTIVITIES**

- I am keen on improving my coding skills in my spare time, such as clean code, solid principles in each programming language, coding tips and tricks, web3, etc...
- I am an active person who likes to bring joy to others. My hobbies are playing musical instruments and singing, playing sports like football, badminton and running. I have completed a trail race (15km), a half marathon (21km) and a full marathon (42km).
- In my free time, I also work on some pet projects. They can be found at my GitHub profile <a href="https://github.com/cvthang56th2">https://github.com/cvthang56th2</a>